<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
     xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
     xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>48</title>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Collected from a digital image by <persName role="collection">M. H.
                            Beals</persName>. Transcribed by <persName role="transcription">Max
                            Templer</persName>.</authority>
                    <availability>
                        <licence>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0
                            International License</licence>
                    </availability>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                        <titleStmt>
                            <title>Glasgow Advertiser</title>
                        </titleStmt>
                        <publicationStmt>
                            <authority>Text within the public domain. </authority>
                            <pubPlace>
                                <address>
                        <settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
                        <region>Scotland</region>
                        <country>United Kingdom</country>
                     </address>
                            </pubPlace>
                            <date when="1789-12-18"/>
                        </publicationStmt>
                    </biblFull>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
            <profileDesc>
                <textDesc>
                    <channel mode="w"/>
                    <constitution type="single"/>
                    <derivation type="original"/>
                    <domain type="public"/>
                    <factuality type="mixed"/>
                    <interaction type="none" active="corporate" passive="world"/>
                    <preparedness type="revised"/>
                    <purpose type="persuade"/>
                </textDesc>
                <textClass>
                    <keywords>
                        <list>
                            <item>trade</item>
                            <item>Anglo-American relations</item>
                            <item>religion</item>
                        </list>
                    </keywords>
                </textClass>
            </profileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>
            <pb/>The Minister is now said to be employed in <lb/>drawing up two plans, which
                    will give rise to <lb/>very warm debates in Parliament : one is for set<lb break="no"/>tling a commercial arrangement between Great <lb/>Britain and
                    Ireland ; the other for giving a con<lb break="no"/>stitution to Canada. In
                    feeling the former, the <lb/>Minister will have to contend with strong com<lb break="no"/>mercial prejudices; in the latter, he will have to
                    <lb/>encounter religious principles. The British <lb/>settlers in Canada are
                    comparatively few in num<lb break="no"/>ber. The great bulk of the Canadians are
                    the <lb/>descendants of French, and are Roman Catho<lb break="no"/>lics. The
                    former are Protestants.</p>
                <p>Fleaury in france, and Walpole in England, <lb/>were not fonder of peace than Mr.
                    Pitt. Con<lb break="no"/>quests may be made by war, but consequence and
                    <lb/>wealth can only be obtained by a pacific system, <lb/>if the first
                    commercial nation in the world.</p>
                <p>Besides these considerations, the grand secret <lb/>has been discovered since the
                    present Minister <lb/>came into power, that the best riddance England <lb/>ever
                    had, was of her American Colonies ; because <lb/>by this means, she becomes
                    thoroughly collected <lb/>at home, to oppose every foreign power, without
                    <lb/>the expence and blood of supporting the Ameri<lb break="no"/>cans, at the
                    same time that they cannot do with<lb break="no"/>out BRitish manufactures in
                    one line or another.</p>
                <p>Thus, they are under the necessity of protect<lb break="no"/>ing themselves, at
                    the same time, that, like the <lb/>rest of Europe, they are obliged to resort to
                    our <lb/>superior mercantile market.</p>
                <p>Application has been lately made to the Lords <lb/>of the Treasury for an order
                    on the Bank to issue <lb/>some of the new silver coin, in aid of the pre<lb break="no"/>sent want of silver for circulation, the scarcity <lb/>of which
                    is much felt by retail traders in par<lb break="no"/>ticular.</p>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
