<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
     xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
     xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>165</title>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority> Collected from a digital image on by M. H. Beals. Transcribed by
                            <persName>Max Templer</persName>. </authority>
                    <availability>
                        <licence>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0
                            International License</licence>
                    </availability>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                        <titleStmt>
                            <title>Glasgow Advertiser</title>
                        </titleStmt>
                        <publicationStmt>
                            <authority>Text within the public domain. </authority>
                            <pubPlace>
                     <address>
                        <settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
                        <region>Scotland</region>
                        <country>United Kingdom</country>
                     </address>
                  </pubPlace>
                            <date when="1820-05-22"/>
                        </publicationStmt>
                    </biblFull>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
            <profileDesc>
                <textDesc>
                    <channel mode="w"/>
                    <constitution type="single"/>
                    <derivation type="original"/>
                    <domain type="public"/>
                    <factuality type="mixed"/>
                    <interaction type="none" active="corporate" passive="world"/>
                    <preparedness type="revised"/>
                    <purpose type="inform"/>
                </textDesc>
                <textClass>
                    <keywords>
                        <list>
                            <item>disease</item>
                            <item>shipping news</item>
                        </list>
                    </keywords>
                </textClass>
            </profileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>
            <pb n="4"/> Extract of a letter received from Calcutta, dated <lb/>22d November,
                    1819:--"An afflicting circumstance <lb/>has recently taken place. The Captain of
                    the Bengal, <lb/>a Liverpool trader, very lately gave a ball on board <lb/>his
                    ship, which was about to sail for England. The <lb/>party was very small, and
                    more than half were taken <lb/>ill with a violent fever immediately afterwards.
                    I <lb/>buried the Captain and the Surgeon a few days after <lb/>it; not less
                    than ten of the part died within as many <lb/>days, all younger persons. Only
                    one officer survives <lb/>of those who left England in the ship, and he is just
                    <lb/>recovering in the Hospital. All sorts of conjectures <lb/>were made, but it
                    turns out that there were 17,000 <lb/>undressed buffalo horns in the hold, in a
                    complete <lb/>state of putrefaction. This vessel has sailed for Eng<lb break="no"/>land in this state without a Surgeon. I question <lb/>whether it
                    will ever arrive; it ought not to be ad<lb break="no"/>mitted among other
                    shipping if it does;–the opening <lb/>of the hold will be death to him
                    who does it, and per<lb break="no"/>haps to many more."--In consequence of this
                        disas<lb break="no"/>trous information, Ministers have issued an order for
                    <lb/>the vessel, on her arrival at Liverpool, or any other <lb/>part, to undergo
                        quarantine.–<hi rend="italic">London Paper.</hi>
         </p>
                <p> All apprehension on the above subject is complete<lb break="no"/>ly done away by
                    the following letter from Liverpool, <lb/>May 14:– </p>
                <p> "I noticed a paragraph in the London papers, <lb/>respecting the Bengal, of this
                    port, at Calcutta, stat<lb break="no"/>ing that a number of deaths had taken
                    place, sup<lb break="no"/>
            <lb/>posed in consequence of the Infectious vapours
                    arising <lb/>from some buffalo horns.–The Bengal arrived here <lb/>April
                    5, and has been discharged without any of <lb/>those dreadful consequences which
                    the medical gen<lb break="no"/>tlemen of Calcutta prognosticated.–I
                    should rather <lb/>suppose that the fatal consequences which ensued <lb/>to
                    those individuals who attended the ball given on <lb/>board this vessel at
                    Calcutta, would be none justly <lb/>attributed to the exposure to night
                    air."</p>
                <p/>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
