<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
     xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
     xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>215</title>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Collected from a digital image by <persName role="collection">M. H.
                            Beals</persName> Transcribed by <persName role="transcription">Max
                            Templer</persName>.</authority>
                    <availability>
                        <licence>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0
                            International License</licence>
                    </availability>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                        <titleStmt>
                            <title>Scotsman</title>
                        </titleStmt>
                        <publicationStmt>
                            <authority>Text within the public domain. </authority>
                            <pubPlace>
                                <address>
                        <settlement>Edinburgh</settlement>
                        <region>Scotland</region>
                        <country>United Kingdom</country>
                     </address>
                            </pubPlace>
                            <date when="1829-11-04"/>
                        </publicationStmt>
                    </biblFull>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
            <profileDesc>
                <textDesc>
                    <channel mode="w"/>
                    <constitution type="single"/>
                    <derivation type="original"/>
                    <domain type="public"/>
                    <factuality type="mixed"/>
                    <interaction type="none" active="corporate" passive="world"/>
                    <preparedness type="revised"/>
                    <purpose type="inform"/>
                </textDesc>
            </profileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>
            <pb/>
            <hi rend="italic">Swan River.</hi>–The ship Warrior, Stone,
                        command<lb break="no"/>er, bound to Swan River, Sydney, and the East Indies,
                    <lb/>sailed for her destination on Friday, from Portsmouth, <lb/>with prospects
                    of favourable weather in her progress <lb/>down the Channel. The Warrior is a
                    fine vessel of <lb/>about 700 tons burden, and carried out upwards of 250
                    <lb/>passengers to the new settlement. Several of the pas<lb break="no"/>sengers
                    are persons of independent fortune, who have <lb/>embarked considerable property
                    in the speculation ; and <lb/>and two ofthem, named Byrne and Molloy, paid the
                    <lb/>enormous sum of L1,000 for the best accommodation <lb/>the vessel could
                    afford their families and suite. Six <lb/>pianos are on board the Warrior, and a
                    proportionate <lb/>number of fair and accomplished vocalists and musicians
                    <lb/>of course accompany the instruments to their destina<lb break="no"/>tion.
                    The Warrior has also on board fifty dogs of the <lb/>choicest breed, several
                    pens of sheep, considerable <lb/>number of swine, two milch cows, and three
                    valuable <lb/>horses ; but, as tempestuous weather may be antici<lb break="no"/>pated on the vessel reaching the Bay of Biscay, appre<lb break="no"/>hensions
                    are entertained that a portion of the live cargo <lb/>must be consigned to the
                    ocean before the termination <lb/>of the voyage. It is calculated that, from the
                        advan<lb break="no"/>tageous arrangements entered into by the commander
                    <lb/>and a gentleman named Semple, who has chartered the <lb/>Warrior, and gone
                    out in her, they will clear the enor<lb break="no"/>mous sum of L10,000 by the
                    voyage.</p>
                <p/>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
