<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
     xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
     xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>7</title>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority> Collected from a digital image on by M. H. Beals. Transcribed by
                            <persName>Max Templer</persName>. </authority>
                    <availability>
                        <licence>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0
                            International License</licence>
                    </availability>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                        <titleStmt>
                            <title>Glasgow Advertiser</title>
                        </titleStmt>
                        <publicationStmt>
                            <authority>Text within the public domain. </authority>
                            <pubPlace>
                     <address>
                        <settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
                        <region>Scotland</region>
                        <country>United Kingdom</country>
                     </address>
                  </pubPlace>
                            <date when="1789-07-20"/>
                        </publicationStmt>
                    </biblFull>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
            <profileDesc>
                <textDesc>
                    <channel mode="w"/>
                    <constitution type="single"/>
                    <derivation type="original"/>
                    <domain type="public"/>
                    <factuality type="mixed"/>
                    <interaction type="none" active="corporate" passive="world"/>
                    <preparedness type="revised"/>
                    <purpose type="inform"/>
                </textDesc>
                <textClass>
                    <keywords>
                        <list>
                            <item>agriculture</item>
                            <item>trade</item>
                        </list>
                    </keywords>
                </textClass>
            </profileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>
            <pb/>
            <hi rend="center">
               <hi rend="italic">Extract of a letter from a Gentleman in
                            Bermuda to</hi>
            </hi>
            <lb/>
            <hi rend="center">
               <hi rend="italic">his friend
                            in Norfolk, Virginia, dated April</hi> 2.</hi>
         </p>
                <p> "By Captain Gilbert, the bearer of this <lb/>you will learn our distress for
                    want of provi- <lb/>sions: There has not been in the whole island <lb/>one
                    bushel of corn for sale for 16 days past. <lb/>Capt. George, from Baltimore,
                    brought in [?] <lb/>days ago two bushels of corn, which sold immed<lb break="no"/>diately at 6s. 8d. per bushel; he also brought in <lb/>360 barrels of flour,
                    common and superfine, which <lb/>sold at eight and nine dollars per barrel. No
                        ves<lb break="no"/>sel has arrived here with provisions since Capt.
                    <lb/>George; and no vessel belonging to the island is <lb/>expected to relieve
                    us. A great number of poor <lb/>people have been for ten days past obliged to
                    live <lb/>on the greens of the field. Governor Hamilton, <lb/>by advice of his
                    counsel, has opened the port of <lb/>Bermuda to all foreign vessels whatever,
                    for thirty <lb/>days, to be computed from the 30th day of March, <lb/>laden with
                    bread, corn; or flour. He also allows, <lb/>for three months, the importation of
                    salted pro<lb break="no"/>visions from any foreign port whatever, in vessels
                    <lb/>belonging to these islands. IT is said, what if any <lb/>foreign vessel
                    should come here after the time per<lb break="no"/>mited by proclamation, they
                    will be allowed to <lb/>dispose of their cargo, if they can prove they set
                    <lb/>out with an intent to come here. If any vessels <lb/>be ready to sail from
                    Norfolk, with provisions, ad<lb break="no"/>vise them to call at Bermuda."</p>
                <p/>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
